

Curriculum Vitae for Max Akira Endo Kokubun

Personal information

Address: Waldemars Hage 3 E-mail: max@xal.no

0175 Oslo Phone: +47 922 98 573

Born: 24.01.1986 Nationality: Brazilian

Summary

In essence, I am a problem-solver who relies on my extense scientific knowledge and experience in academia. I have a PhD in Aerospace Engineering, from the National Institute for Space Research (INPE, 2014) and before joining Expert Analytics, I held two postdoctoral positions, one in Applied Mathematics, at the National Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics (IMPA, 2014-2016), and one in Chemistry/Applied Mathematics, at the University of Bergen (UiB, 2016-2019). The focus of my projects was on Enhanced Oil Recovery, through combustion (IMPA) and polymer particles (UiB). Thus, I have expertise in developing mathematical/physical models and performing numerical simulations for fluid mechanics problems (CFD). I worked in close collaboration with researchers from different backgrounds (physicists, engineers, mathematicians, experimentalist chemists, etc) and international institutions (Norway, Brazil, USA, Netherlands, Sweden, Belgium, UK). Therefore, I have excellent communication skills and can easily connect with both technical and non-technical audiences.

Technical skills

Frameworks Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib

Languages Matlab, Python, Fortran, Octave

Tools openFOAM, COMSOL, Mathematica, gmsh, Latex

Education

2011 - 2014 PhD in Aerospace Engineering. National Institute for Space Rese-

arch, Brazil. "Theoretical Study of Diffusion Flames Originated from the Burning of Heavy Liquid Fuels in Low Porosity Media (In-Situ

Combustion)"

2009 - 2011	Master in Aerospace Engineering. National Institute for Space Re-
	search, Brazil. "Analytical Analysis of Liquid Fuel Combustion Estab-
	lished in a Low-Porosity Medium"
2004 - 2008	Bachelor in Physics. Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.

Professional experience

2013 - 2014	Visiting Scholar. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA
2014 - 2016	Postdoctoral Fellow. National Institute for Pure and Applied Mathe-
	matics, Brazil
2016 - 2019	Postdoctoral Fellow. University of Bergen, Norway
2020	Consultant. Expert Analytics, Norway

Languages

English	Fluent
Norwegian	Good
Portuguese	Native
Spanish	Good

Personal skills

Analytical thinking Communication	I have a facility in understanding complex problems in an organized matter, breaking it down into smaler, easier to understand pieces. I am considered an excellent communicator, specifically regarding sim-
	plifying very technical topics to the broader audience.
Problem	I like solving real-world problems by analysing them through my scien-
solving	tific background.
Team work	I enjoy being part of a team when solving problems. My experience in research was always guided by collaborative work, absorbing knowledge from more experienced researchers and guiding younger researchers.

Some interests and hobbies

Personal	Traveling, Hiking, Sports (football, swimming, rollerblading, tennis),
	Music
Scientific	Fluid Mechanics, Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD), Porous

media, Enhanced Oil Recovery, Machine Learning, Data Science

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity Experimentally-based modelling of colloid transport in multiphase porous media (EPOCH)

expertanalytics.no

Period 2016-2019

Role Postdoctoral Fellow

Staffing 8 Researchers

Volume 100

Description This project was funded by Equinor and it aimed at developing mathe-

matical models and numerical solvers for the problem of polymer particles transport in oil-water flow in porous media. The models we developed were based on experimentally-obtained results for enhan-

ced oil recovery.

Tools openFOAM, MRST, COMSOL

Activity Mathematical modelling and analysis of medium-temperature oxida-

tion (MTO) of multicomponent oil flow in porous media

Period 2014-2016

Role Postdoctoral Fellow Staffing 4 Researchers

Volume 100

Description Development of mathematical models and numerical solvers for the

problem of reactive multiphase flow of a multicomponent oil in porous media. This project was part of IMPA's strategy to tackle industry-relevant problems by the use of high-level mathematical and numerical tools. Our theoretical results were compared with experimental results

from a collaborative research team at TU Delft.

Tools Mathematica, COMSOL, Matlab

Activity Asymptotic analysis of a chambered diffusion flame

Period 2013-2014
Role Visiting Scholar
Staffing 3 Researchers

Volume 100

Description Analysis of the extinction limits of a diffusion flame established in

porous media. This collaborative work between INPE and the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA, was part of my PhD project. This work identified the similarities between the extinction of a diffusion flame established in a porous matrix and the extinction of spread flames in solid fuels. The novelty of this work was recognized by The Combustion Institute, who awarded it the prize of Distinguished

Paper in the 36th International Symposium on Combustion.

Tools Matlab, Fortran